自动字幕整理+翻译：SuperBart  原作者LGR于2021-3-10在LGR Blurbs上发布
Hey, look at this! Got a registered WinRAR CD-ROM that just arrived in the mail.
大家来看看啊，我的WinRAR CD终于到货了!
Greetings! Just blurb here about this,
大家好，我给大家说说这张CD
which is a follow-up to my video that I did over on LGR, where I registered WinRAR.
这是我那期激活WinRAR视频的续集
Because... why not? It's a fun thing to do I suppose in 2021.
这是我今年干的最有意思的事情了
And yeah, there was an option to order a physical CD-ROM
没错，当时我买WinRAR许可的时候
whenever I bought the full WinRAR registration thing.
有个寄送CD的选项
So, let's just open it up.
那么，现在赶紧启封吧
And yep, it's a CD-R. I figured it would be.
好吧，就是张刻录CD，跟我猜的差不多
Nothing else in there.
里面只有这个
And all right, look at that. It's actually a nicer label than I thought it would be.
再看看CD吧，上面的印刷面比我想的要好
It's uh, not the highest resolution, but that's fine.
尽管不是最佳印刷分辨率，不过还好
RARLAB WinRAR physical delivery CD.
RARLAB WinRAR 的实体寄送光盘
Note: If the WinRAR install menu doesn't appear, double-click autorun.exe
注意：如果WinRAR安装程序没有启动，双击"autorun.exe"
Well, that answers another question too.
好吧，这句话解开了我的一个疑惑
I was wondering if it would just be just the key file on a CD，
我当时想：这张光盘上会不会只有密钥文件
or if it would also have any kind of executable for some version of WinRAR,
还是会有某些版本的WinRAR安装程序
or... Who knows! I didn't know what to expect.
或是......谁知道呢！我也不知道会有啥了
And amusingly, neither did one of my patrons (the LGR patrons),
还有件有意思的事，我的一位赞助人联系我了
注：赞助网址 https://www.patreon.com/LazyGameReviews
who got in touch, and apparently, actually works for the company,
很明显，他是为这张CD的制造商，CleverBridge公司工作
that puts these things together, the CleverBridge.
So yeah, when I was going through the checkout,
确实，当我购买WinRAR许可
I noticed that it was CleverBridge taking care of the physical... stuff.
快结账时，我注意到实体CD部分
and just the whole checkout process for registering WinRAR.
会由这家公司处理
And yeah, they said that:
当然，他们还说
"Love of videos, happy to work for CleverBridge
您的视频很有意思，为公司工作很高兴
and we at cv enjoyed the WinRAR video.
我们的同事很喜欢您做的WinRAR视频
The Flux video was also a good laugh.
那期 Flux 软件的视频也很好玩
As the CD came from digital river and was classic."
毕竟CD是数码时代的产物，是十分经典的
So yeah, that was a another kind of similar thing I've shown here in blurbs before.
对了，他说的视频我之前是发在随心说频道上的
注：LGR Blurb频道上传了Flex游戏的CD，也是张刻录光盘
It's just taking a look at the physical version of Flux you could still order.
那期视频，我订购了一份Flux软件的实体版
Which, is a lot crappier than this one, in terms of the release.
当然，和这个相比，那个还要更差
It was also on a burn CD. But yeah, there was even less going on with that.
那个也是刻录CD，但是，上面的东西更少
Anyway, two things worth pointing out.
无论如何，他提到了两件事
"The CD label often are printed your order reference number.
CD上通常会印有你的订单号
You might want to sharpen it out for the blurbs."
你最好在制作视频时给盖上
I don't see that on here...
然而我并没有看到......
There's that, little tiny thing but... you know.
应该是这个小东西吧，不过......可惜还是录进去了
Uh. "As for the label design, if there is one.
至于印刷面设计，要是有亮点的话
I would look it up, but that's no fun. "
我会说说的，不过真的是没啥可说的
So, hey~ There is a label and it's got the WinRAR logo, partially on there.
好吧，印刷面上真有点东西，就是不完整的WinRAR标志
Let's put it into a Windows PC, check it out see exactly
现在咱赶紧将其装入电脑，看看光盘里面
what's on here, which version it is.
到底有啥，里面是啥版本的软件吧
All right, so first thing, we're going to try it on is the Megaluminum Monster,
好的，这会我用这台电脑演示
with Windows 98 loaded here.
目前运行 Windows 98
I genuinely don't know which version that it comes with,
我确实不知道里面到底存的是啥版本的软件
so it might not even be compatible.
兴许还无法兼容呢
But you know, it's WinRAR. Hopefully it is. We'll see.
不过，里面一定装的是WinRAR，希望能用吧。我们来看看
"UDF volume" is the label there. Very creative.
光盘名称叫“UDF volume”，挺有创意的:-|
注：直译为UDF卷，UDF是统一光盘格式（Universal Disc Format）的缩写
Although we see 306MB capacity.
光盘上有306MB数据
Oh boy, an autorun.
天哪，有自动执行程序
We need a larger resolution than this, don't we?
得搞个高些的分辨率才行
Okay, 800 by 600. Let's not tile that. There we go.
好的，800x600. 壁纸就别平铺了
Let's try that one more time!
好的，我们再来一遍
Get a GhostInstaller, here we go.
好的，启动了GhostInstaller
"Welcome to the WinRAR physical delivery on CD"
"欢迎来到WinRAR实体寄送CD"
That is so weird to even see.
看上去真奇怪
Anyway, the CD contains WinRAR and your registration key file.
无论如何，里面存有WinRAR安装程序和注册密钥文件
Okay, so it's got both. I was hoping so, considering it's got 306MB.
确实，两个都有，毕竟都有306MB大小了
Now let's just see what's actually on here at all.
现在我要看看里面存的到底是啥
(Now I don't want to do that.)
(现在先别自动运行)
All right, so autorun, WinRAR key.
好的，自动运行程序，授权密钥文件
So there's the same "rarreg.key" file, which not in WinRAR itself, so that's cool.
这个"rarreg.key"文件没有内置在软件本体，有点意思
You can just drop that into the directory of WinRAR to register it,
你可以直接将其扔进WinRAR安装目录来激活
or you can do what I did in my registration video.
或是学我上期视频那样来用
I don't know, extravaganza thing on LGR.
怎么说呢，无限激活WinRAR老版本吧
(Some) different stuff here some...
这个目录有所不同
Wow! Oh, look at all these.
看看这些(⊙ˍ⊙)
So it's WinRAR 6 and down to WinRAR 5
这里有32位和64位的各语言版
in all kinds of different languages, 32-bit and 64-bit.
WinRAR，版本号有5的，有6的
And it's slowly loading in the icons for them, oh dear.
天哪，加载图标的时间太长了
Oh, what the difference is, between this WinRAR key folder and the other one.
好的，我发现两个“WinRAR key”的区别是
Okay, so it's just a html file letting you know how to do it. Simple enough.
这里面有一个HTML文档，告诉你怎么使用密钥文件，挺好理解的
Well, now I'm actually hopeful that this will actually work on Windows 98 SE. We'll see it.
好吧，我希望 Win98 SE 能够运行最新版的 WinRAR 吧
"32-bit/64-bit version of Windows..."
（翻译下载7zip去了，并对360压缩来了一个mid-finger）
Cool, let's just run through the installer here.
好吧，现在赶紧安装吧
Ah, so two different options. Register WinRAR and Install.
好吧，有两个选项，注册WinRAR或是安装
We don't have it actually on this system.
这个系统是没装WinRAR的
I mean, I did when I did the installation video.
当然，上个视频我是安装过的
But I took it off of there for this.
不过为了这期视频，我给卸载了
So we can choose between 32-bit and 64-bit.
你看，我们可以选择32位版或64位版
And we can choose the version.
我们也可以选择语言和版本
Looks like the only English one is 6.0
看样子带英语语言包的软件只有6.0版本
And it expects a newer version of Windows.
然后它需要更高版本的 Windows
Well, that kind of uh, answers that question, a number of questions.
好吧，这倒是解开我很多的疑问
Really, this is a lot... better of a CD than I was expecting.
说真的，这张CD比我想象的还要有料
I mean, seriously, it's uh, yeah, 300 MB of WinRAR goodness. More or less.
怎么说呢，至少有300 MB的 WinRAR 相关文件呢
It's a shame they didn't label it. ”UDF volume", at least call it ”WinRAR“.
只可惜他们没有给光盘取名，至少也应该叫”WinRAR“吧
Ah it's a small thing, just labeling your CDs.
不过只是件小事情，不过是给光盘取名罢了
Anyway, I don't know exactly which version of windows that
不过，我还是不知道盘上最老的版本能支持多老的Windows
supports in terms of the oldest one,
but we'll switch over to the Windows XP here real quick to see if that works.
我马上更新到Windows XP系统来看看到底如何吧
And the way I do that on this one is as simple as taking out the...
这个过程十分简单，你只需将...
SuperBart:以下过程可概括为”LiveSD“
SD card and loading up...
SD卡拔出，然后插入...
another operating system and I've got a number of them here.
装有另一个操作系统的SD卡，我有很多的
So we will choose Windows XP SP3 here.
这里我选择 Windows XP SP3
Just insert the SD card.
只需插入SD卡
And that's that. This is using a scuzzy 2 SD interface so...
然后就OK了，这里我使用的是 SCSI2SD
注: scuzzy原因是邋遢的，烦人的。在计算机领域，专指SCSI接口。
这个硬件是可以把SD卡当作硬盘使用，用于上古机器，官网SCSI2SD.COM
Yeah, I don't know. Come to think of it.
Emmm...突然想到
I don't know if I've actually done a video on that
我还没有说过用SD卡
whole little setup down there. it's quite nice.
加载系统啥的，这真的很不错呢
Just being able to swap around different operating systems
只要换SD卡，就能在相同的硬件上
and whatnot on the exact same hardware.
更换不同的系统
Just cause these 2 SD. It's that thing.
只需使用SCSI2SD就可以了
Come on! windows xp it does load a bit slowly for...
快点啊！Windows XP装在在SD卡上
this operating system on these SD cards in this interface.
经过SCSI接口传输，加载得真慢啊
注：这个东西的普通版读存取速率均约为2.5MB/s
高级版能有10MB/s的速度
I don't really recommend it for newer OSes like this,
我不太建议将较新的系统装在SD卡上
but for DOS, Windows 95, 98, especially even millennium edition,
但对于我提到的这些系统，他能工作得很好，甚至超出了我的预期
it works good enough, more than enough for what I do.
Yeah.
o(￣▽￣)ｄ
SuperBart:我看到了宝石迷阵2，我第一个买来的游戏，花了18元。
Actually I haven't used this new Model F on this system yet.
实际上我还没有在这个系统上使用 Model F 键盘呢
注: 该键盘由IBM最早由1981年生产出来。
I mean, you know, I have on this PC, but not the Windows XP installation here.
当然，电脑装上了这个键盘，但电脑在此之前没有运行过XP
And there it is, myleskeyboards.com ...
好的，他侦测到了
All right, back to this. Let's try this one more time, install WinRAR.
好的，我们再来一次，安装WinRAR
Actually, do I already have it on here?
等会，我安装过WinRAR吗
No, I don't.
并没有
32-bit version, English 6.
32位英语版，版本号是6.0
And that's that. Go for everything.
就这样了，一切运行良好
And I mean, it doesn't really matter. Because I'm probably uninstall this anyway.
这个无所谓的，最终我也会卸载它的B-)
唯一指定网址：https://www.7-zip.org/
I use 7-zip normally, so really doesn't matter. It's one to test it out really quick.
我平常用7-zip，所以没关系的，我只想赶紧测试一下
Uh, and yeah, it looks like...
好的，看上去应该......
Okay, so it hasn't registered it yet after the installation.
好吧，安装好并没有自动注册
press back to select another program.
请按”回退“按钮以选择另一个程序
Uh, I'd like to register it. Let's try that.
我现在要注册，所以选那个吧
I was kind of hoping it would install and register at the same time.
我原以为这玩意安装完能自动注册呢
Looks like this little bit here is the html file, that was on.
看上去这就是那个HTML文件了
This area, yeah.
就在这里
Anyway
好的
Anyway.
好的.
Anyway..
好的..
Anyway..!
好的..!
Anyway..! Oh.
’(°ー°〃)
"Can not open..." Now it's looking for the "rarkey.rar".
"无法打开......"看上去它找不到"rarkey.rar"了
Right, it's not... it's not it.
本......本不该这样的啊
Huh! I wonder why?
对吧，怎么会这样呢？
Yeah, because as we determined earlier...
好吧，我们早先说过
It's just a straight up key file that
当你在网上花钱注册的时候
it comes with not the RAR version that you get when you register it online.
CD上的版本和你当时买的时候的版本有所脱节
Even though... if you saw my registration video,
尽管......如果你看了上期视频的话
we just opened that "rarkey" file as a rar.
我们直接用WinRAR打开了"rarkey"文件
SuperBart：原文说是把注册密钥文件当作rar文件打开，总觉得不对劲
And then that automatically registered it.
然后他就自动注册了
So whatever I guess we'll just copy it over directly into the... directory
所以我猜，我们只需将文件直接拷进安装文件夹
and... see if that works.
然后应该能用了
There it is. It is registered to me, single PC usage license.
好了，我的WinRAR注册过了，单电脑使用授权
And yes, that does mean when they say single PC, they really mean single user.
当然，这里说是单电脑授权，而不是单用户授权
The EULA actually allows you to install it on any computers, tablets phones,
最终用户许可协议允许你安装到任意数目的电脑，平板，手机上
what have you... that you have, as long as you're the sole user of it.
只要这些电子设备只有你能用就行了
So, some people were getting on me about that in the comments
当然，那期视频的底下有很多人说
about the registration. Like "Oh! You broke the EULA!"
注册的事，认为我违反了最终用户许可协议
As if it really matters, but no!
好像多大点事赛的，不过我可没有违反！
Section six: Single computer usage license.
第六章 单一计算机使用许可证
注：此处照抄WinRAR的EULA，可见该软件真的是很良心了
当然没有我的字幕授权协议强
”Home users may use their single computer usage license
”家庭用户可以将他们的单一计算机使用许可证，用于授权用户
on all computers and mobile devices, which are property of the license owner.
所拥有的全部计算机和移动设备（优盘，外接硬盘等）上，商业
Business users require more than one license per computer."
用户在每台安装本软件的计算机或移动设备上都需要一份许可证"
Am I a business? Uh, I mean, I'm just the only one using it.
我是商业用户吗......等会，只有我使用这个软件啊
So EULA's license agreement, it's a thing.
好的，EULA这点事我说完了
So anyway that pretty much answers the question of
好了，大家应该都知道购买WinRAR许可后
what is on the WinRAR CD-ROM when you register it，
WinRAR CD-ROM 上到底存了些什么
and get a copy sent to you physically from CleverBridge.
还从 CleverBridge 公司得到了一个实体版软件
That's really cool. I mean, it's on a CD-R!
真是挺好的，这可是刻录光盘啊！
SuperBart:这张CD由于存着注册密钥文件，所以全球独此一份，不过价格不菲
210元软件授权+70元光盘，我还是用7zip吧......
Eh... But it's better than nothing, in my opinion.
在我看来，毕竟聊胜于无
And it's just a nifty little collectible to have :-)
而且这小玩意挺适合收藏的呢
So uh, yeah, thank you for watching this blurb.
好的，我说完了，感谢大家收看！